sketchymedical.com 2015-04-08

# SketchyMicro – Medical Microbiology Review for the USMLE Step 1 | Privacy Policy

Last updated: September 16, 2013

SketchyMicro, as operated by Sketchy Group, LLC, (hereafter “SketchyMicro”) is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our website and services.

This policy will let you know:

  * How and when you are consenting to this privacy policy;
  * SketchyMicro’s position on the use of its site by minors and the collection of personal information from minors;
  * What personally identifiable information SketchyMicro collects from you;
  * What cookies are and how SketchyMicro use them;
  * How SketchyMicro uses your information and with whom your information is shared;
  * SketchyMicro’s policy regarding linked websites and embedded services;
  * What your choices are regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information;
  * What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information;
  * How long your personal data kept;
  * What we don’t do;
  * What else you should know about your privacy;
  * When this policy is effective and how and when changes may be made.

**Consent  
**By submitting personal information to us (through the use of this website and/or signing up to receive more information) you agree that we may collect, use and disclose such personal information in accordance with this privacy policy and as permitted or required by law. If you do not agree with these terms, please do not provide any personal information to us. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, or if you choose not to provide us with any required personal information, we may not be able to provide you with the services of this website and/or advertisements and services that can be offered on our site only if we have access certain personal information.

**Minors  
**Minors (as defined under the laws of THEIR jurisdiction or residence) are not eligible to use the SketchyMicro website or Services in any way. While we do encourage a healthy interest in medicine in youngsters, this Site was not designed for use by minors and we do not knowingly collect personal information from any minor, and we will not use this information if we discover that it has been provided by a minor.

**What personally identifiable information does SketchyMicro collect from you?  
**SketchyMicro collects information in several ways. Some personal information is gathered when you sign up for services. When submitting a request for services, SketchyMicro asks for your basic biographical information, such as name, email address, phone number, and date of birth (to verify eligibility to sign up for services). This information is necessary to provide additional information to sign up for SketchyMicro, and is provided voluntarily in order to take advantage of our services.

In addition, we may ask you for additional personal information at other times, including, but not limited to, when you inquire about, or sign up for, additional services or participate in promotions or contests. If you contact SketchyMicro we may keep a record of that correspondence. Whenever SketchyMicro collects personal information we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page.

**When we advertise on third party sites  
**When you visit a site on which we advertise and click through our advertisement, we may employ the use cookies pixel tags. The information that we collect through this technology is not personally identifiable.

**When you call or write to our Customer Service  
**When you call or write to our Customer Service, we collect contact information, such as name, phone number, mailing address or e-mail address.

**What are cookies and how does SketchyMicro use them?  
**SketchyMicro may use cookies to store and sometimes track information about you. A “cookie” is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. Generally, we use cookies to:

_Estimate our audience size and track interest in our services_ – Each browser accessing the SketchyMicro website may be given a unique cookie which is then used to determine the extent of repeat usage and to help target advertisements based on user interests and behavior.

_Save user login information_ – Each user may have the option to stay logged in to their account, which is an option made possible through the use of cookies.

SketchyMicro also collects IP addresses for system administration and to report aggregate information to our partners or service providers.

**How does SketchyMicro use your information and with whom is your information shared?  
**SketchyMicor’s primary goal in collecting personal information is in providing you the best service possible through its website. The majority of information that is collected about you is for the purpose of verifying contact information and delivering requested information and services.

SketchyMicro may retain your contact information for as long as permitted by law and as long as is necessary to permit you to use our services without the requirement of resubmitting the same information.

Except as provided herein, SketchyMicro shall not sell, rent, trade or otherwise transfer any personal and/or traffic data or communications content to any third party without your explicit permission, unless it is obliged to do so under applicable laws or by order of the competent authorities.

Your information may be used to effect a corporate transaction, in connection with the sale, merger, spin-off or other corporate reorganization of our corporation, where the information is provided to the new controlling entity in regular course of business. In the event of such an occurrence, every effort will be made by SketchyMicro to inform you of the transfer of your personal information.

Your information may be disclosed as is required by our insurers and by regulatory agencies or to employees, contractors, consultants, and agents of SketchyMicro to perform necessary actions in the normal course of business. No more information than is required in these circumstances will be provided.

**Linked websites and embedded services  
**SketchyMicro may contain links that will let you leave SketchyMicro’s website and access another website (e.g. YouTube). Similarly, portions of this site may employ the use of embedded services from third-parties, such as for the processing of credit card transactions and video delivery. These “linked websites” are not under the control of SketchyMicro and it is possible that these websites have a different privacy policy. This policy applies solely to personal information that is acquired on this website (www.sketchymicro.com). SketchyMicro accepts no responsibility or liability for your use or disclosure of personal information to linked websites.

**What are your choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information?  
**The disclosure of personal information is required to create an account on our site, which is required to access certain information and services. If you do not wish to disclose the requisite information you are free to discontinue use of the SketchyMicro website.

You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies the SketchyMicro website may not be displayed or function in the way intended by SketchyMicro.

**What is SketchyMicro’s policy on allowing you to update, correct, or delete your personally identifiable information?  
**If you wish to update, correct, or delete any of the information about you stored by SketchyMicro, send an inquiry to support@sketchymicro.com. To protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

**What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information?  
**SketchyMicro shall take the appropriate organizational and technical measures to protect the personal information and IP data provided to it or collected by it necessary to comply fully with any and all applicable laws, obligations, and regulations.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, SketchyMicro cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

**How long is your personal information stored?**  
SketchyMicro will retain your personal information and IP information as long as is permitted by applicable laws and regulations.

**What we do NOT do  
**We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, login name, or password, in an unsecure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. Additionally we will not request any confidential or personal information through a social networking site such as Twitter™, MySpace™, or Facebook™.

**What else should you know about your privacy?  
**If you choose to use the SketchyMicro website you should be aware that any information transmitted electronically via the World Wide Web might not be secure. SketchyMicro assumes no liability for the loss of any information that you transmit to us via the World Wide Web.

We may release personal information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with a law; to enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other policies; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of SketchyMicro, our employees, our users, or others

In communicating with you, we may send e-mail as unencrypted plain text because we are aware that most customers cannot easily process encrypted e-mail. This is done for your convenience, but with the security concern that, if misrouted or intercepted, it could be read more easily than encrypted e-mail.

**Effective date of this policy and future modification  
**This privacy policy is effective as of 09/16/2013. SketchyMicro reserves the right to make changes, deletions, modifications, or provide supplements to this policy from time to time. Changes will apply to the information collected after the date of changes as well as to existing information held by us and will take effect immediately upon publication, unless otherwise stated in writing by SketchyMicro. You agree that the express acceptance by you, or your continued use of the SketchyMicro website after publication of changes, shall constitute your acceptance of the privacy policy.
